(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
よみがえれ
Revive
天音かなた2024生誕祭ライブ、いくぞー！
Amane Kanata 2024 Birthday Live, let's go!
空と大地が交差している
The sky and the earth are intersecting
今たたずんでるこの世界で
In this world I'm standing in right now
命が生まれ　また沈んでく
Life is born and then sinks away again
繰り返される営みの中
In the midst of repeated activities
こんなもんかとよぎった瞬間
The moment I thought, "Is this all there is?"
夢は力をなくす
Dreams lose their power
もう一度生まれよ　この場所で
Be born once again in this place
正義のその奥で夢が息づいてる
Deep within justice, a dream is breathing
重なる力を信じて
Believe in the overlapping power
正義のその奥に闇が潜んでいる
Deep within justice, darkness is lurking
見極めろすべてを
See through it all
振り上げた勇気は切り裂くためじゃない
The courage you've brandished isn't meant for tearing apart
引き合う絆で
With the bonds that pull us together
呼び覚ませ
Awaken it
鮮やかに
Vividly
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
傷ついて行き場をなくし
Wounded and with nowhere to go
さまよっているその魂を
That soul which is wandering
癒やす力は心の奥で
The power to heal is deep within the heart
静かに鼓動を刻んでいる
Quietly keeping a pulse
持てる力すべてぶつけ
Hit it with all the power you have
涙を流すのなら
If you're going to shed tears
選ぶべき道は君を待ってる
The path you should choose is waiting for you
失った今と通り過ぎた過去
The lost present and the past that has gone by
狭間であきらめるよりも
Rather than giving up in the gap between them
今日を目をそらさずにここから始めよう
Let's not look away from today and start from here
見極めろ明日を
See through to tomorrow
誰かに見せつける勇気は脱ぎ捨てて
Discard the courage that's just for show
素顔に戻ろう
Let's return to our true faces
呼び覚ませ
Awaken it
鮮やかに
Vividly
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
正義のその奥で夢が息づいてる
Deep within justice, a dream is breathing
重なる力を信じて
Believe in the overlapping power
正義のその奥に闇が潜んでいる
Deep within justice, darkness is lurking
見極めろすべてを
See through it all
振り上げた勇気は切り裂くためじゃない
The courage you've brandished isn't meant for tearing apart
引き合う絆で
With the bonds that pull us together
呼び覚ませ
Awaken it
鮮やかに
Vividly
...believe...
revive a soul
ハイ！みなさんこんかなたー！
Hi! Everyone, Kon-Kanata!
かなたそとっ♡神曲アニソンFes!! ようこそいらっしゃいましたー！
Welcome to Kanata-soto♡ Kami-kyoku Anisong Fes!!
イエーイ、ありがとう！ありがとう！
Yay, thank you! Thank you!
はい！ということで、ハッシュタグは #天音かなた爆誕2024 で、いっぱい呟いてくださーい！
Alright! So, please tweet a lot with the hashtag #AmaneKanataBirthday2024!
頑張るぞ、頑張るぞ、
I'll do my best, I'll do my best,
みんなも頑張ってね。いっぱい呟いてね。
everyone do your best too. Tweet a lot, okay?
ということで、本日お客さん入ってます。ドドーン！ウッパオだー！
So, we have guests today. Ta-da! It's the Uppao!
みなさん知ってますか？ウッパオという存在を。
Do you all know? About the existence of Uppao.
平民じゃなきゃね、ちょっと認知度が低く、あんまりグッズも売れてないんですけれども。
If you're not a Heimin, their recognition is a bit low, and their goods aren't selling that well either...
そんなこと言ったらみんなに愛されるキャラになりました！よかったね、ウッパオ。
But having said that, they've become characters loved by everyone! Good for you, Uppao.
ウッパ役もやっていきつつ、えー、本日頑張っていこうと思います。
While also playing the role of Uppa, I'll do my best today.
たくさんのウッパオに囲まれて歌っていきます。
I'll be singing surrounded by many Uppao.
それでは早速、次の曲参りましょう。いくぞー！
Now then, let's move on to the next song right away. Let's go!
みんなー！もっともっと盛り上がれますかー！？
Everyone! Can you get even more hyped!?
早速、もうゲストが登場します！トップバッターは不知火フレア！
Right away, a guest is appearing! The first batter is Shiranui Flare!
放て！心に刻んだ夢を
Unleash! The dream engraved in my heart
未来さえ置き去りにして
Leaving even the future behind
限界など知らない 意味無い
Knowing no limits, it's meaningless
この力が光散らす
This power scatters the light
その先に遥かな想いを
Sending my distant feelings beyond it
歩いてきたこの道を
This path that I've walked down,
振り返ることしか
if all I can do
出来ないなら 今ここで
is look back, then right here and now,
全てを壊せる
I can destroy everything
暗闇に落ちる街並み
The cityscape falling into darkness,
人はどこまで立ち向かえるの？
how far can people stand against it?
加速するその痛みから
From that accelerating pain,
誰かをきっと守れるよ
I can surely protect someone
Looking! The blitz loop this planet to search-way only my RAILGUN
今すぐ 身体中を光の速さで
Right now, through my whole body at the speed of light,
駆け巡った確かな予感
a certain premonition raced through me
掴め！望むものなら残さず
Seize it! If it's what you want, leave nothing behind
輝ける自分らしさで
with a radiance that is true to yourself
信じてるよあの日の誓いを
I believe in the vow of that day
この瞳に光る涙
The tears shining in these eyes
それさえも強さになるから
even they will become my strength
立ち止まると 少しだけ
When I stop for a moment,
感じる切なさに
the sadness that I feel,
戸惑う事無いなんて
I won't lie and say
嘘はつかないよ
it doesn't bewilder me
空に舞うコインが描く
The trajectory of the coin dancing in the sky
放物線が決める運命
is the parabola that decides my fate
打ち出した答えが今日も
The answer I've sent out today,
私の胸を駆け巡る
too, is racing through my chest
Sparking! The shiny lights awake true desire only my RAILGUN
必ず 貫いてく 戸惑うことなく
I will surely pierce through, without any hesitation
傷ついても 走り続ける
Even if I get hurt, I'll keep on running
凛と煌めく視線は
My dignified and sparkling gaze
狂いなく闇を切り裂く
cuts through the darkness without error
迷いなんて吹き飛ばせばいい
I should just blow away any doubts
この心が叫ぶ限り
as long as this heart of mine screams out
誰ひとり邪魔などさせない
I won't let a single person get in my way
儚く舞う無数の願いは
The countless fleetingly dancing wishes
この両手に積もってゆく
accumulate in these hands of mine
切り裂く闇に見えてくるのは...
What becomes visible in the piercing darkness...
...浮かす
...lifting
切ない記憶
Painful memories
色褪せてく現実に揺れる
Swaying in a fading reality
絶望には負けたくない
I don't want to lose to despair
私が今私であること
That I am who I am right now
胸を張って
Holding my head high
全て誇れる！
I can be proud of everything!
Looking! The blitz loop this planet to search my way
Only my Railgun can shoot it 今すぐ
Only my Railgun can shoot it, right now
身体中を光の速さで
Throughout my body at the speed of light
駆け巡った確かな予感
A certain premonition raced through
放て！心に刻んだ夢を
Release it! The dream carved into my heart
未来さえ置き去りにして
Leaving even the future behind
限界など知らない 意味無い
I don't know limits, they're meaningless
この力が光散らす
This power scatters light
その先
And beyond that
遥かな想いを！
My distant feelings!
素晴らしき世界に今日も乾杯
Cheers to this wonderful world again today
街に飛び交う笑い声も
Even the laughter echoing through the city
見て見ぬフリしてるだけの作りもんさ
Is just a fabrication that everyone ignores
気が触れそうだ
It's enough to drive me mad
クラクラするほどの良い匂いが
A scent so good it makes me dizzy
ツンと刺した鼻の奥 目を覚ます
Pierces deep into my nose and wakes me up
本能のまま今日は誰の番だ
Following instinct, whose turn is it today?
この世界で
In this world
何かができるのか 僕には
What can I do? For me...
何ができるのか
...what can I do?
ただその真っ黒な目から
I just don't want tears to fall...
涙こぼれ落ちないように
...from those pitch-black eyes
願う 未来に何度でもずっと
I pray, forever and ever into the future
喰らいつく
I'll keep hanging on
この間違いだらけの世界の中
Inside this world full of mistakes
君には笑ってほしいから
I want you to be able to smile
もう誰も傷つけない
I won't let anyone get hurt anymore
強く強くなりたいんだよ
I want to become strong, so strong
僕が僕でいられるように
So that I can remain myself
素晴らしき世界は今日も安泰
This wonderful world is peaceful again today
街に渦巻く悪い話も
Even the bad rumors swirling in the city
知らない知らないフリして目を逸らした
I looked away, pretending I didn't know
正気の沙汰じゃないな
This is sheer madness
真面目に着飾った行進
A march dressed up in sincerity
鳴らす足音が弾む 行き先は
The sound of footsteps bounces, the destination...
消えない消えない味が染み付いている
...is stained with an indelible taste
裏側の世界
The world on the other side
今日も答えのない世界の中で願ってるんだよ
In this world without answers, I'm praying today too
不器用だけれど
Clumsy as I am
いつまでも君とただ笑っていたいから
Because I just want to laugh with you forever
跳ねる心臓が体揺らし
My pounding heart shakes my body
叫ぶんだよ
And it's screaming
今こそ動き出せ
Now is the time to start moving
弱い自分を何度でもずっと
Over and over again, my weak self...
喰らいつく
...will keep hanging on
この間違いだらけの世界の中
Inside this world full of mistakes
君には笑ってほしいから
I want you to be able to smile
もう誰も泣かないよう
So that no one has to cry anymore
強く強くなりたいんだよ
I want to become strong, so strong
僕が僕でいられるように
So that I can remain myself
ただ君を守るそのために
Just for the sake of protecting you
走る 走る 走るんだよ
I'll run, run, run
僕の中の僕を超える
To surpass the me inside of me
まるで御伽の話
Just like a fairy tale
終わり迎えた証
A sign that it's come to an end
長すぎる旅路から
From a journey that was far too long
切り出した一節
A passage cut out
それはかつてこの地に影を落とした悪を
The memories of the short journey with the hero
撃ち取りし勇者との短い旅の記憶
who defeated the evil that once cast a shadow over this land.
勇者
作詞・作曲：Ayase
The Brave
Lyrics & Composition: Ayase
物語は終わり 勇者は眠りにつく
The story ends, and the hero goes to sleep,
穏やかな日常をこの地に残して
leaving a peaceful daily life in this land.
時の流れは無情に人を忘れさせる
The passage of time heartlessly makes people forget,
そこに生きた軌跡も錆び付いていく
and the traces of life there begin to rust away.
それでも君の言葉も願いも勇気も
Even so, your words, your wishes, and your courage
今も確かに私の中で生きている
are still certainly living within me today.
同じ道を選んだそれだけだったはずなのに
It should have been just that we chose the same path,
いつの間にかどうして
but before I knew it, why...
頬を伝う涙の理由をもっと知りたいんだ
...do I want to know more about why tears run down my cheeks?
今更だって共に歩んだ旅路を辿れば
Even if it's too late, if I trace back the journey we walked together,
そこに君は居なくともきっと見つけられる
even if you aren't there, I'm sure I can find it.
物語は続く一人の旅路へと発つ
The story continues as I set out on a solo journey,
立ち寄る街で出会う人の記憶の中に残る君は
remaining in the memories of the people I meet in the towns I visit.
相も変わらずお人好しで格好つけてばかりだね
You're still as soft-hearted and showing off as ever, aren't you?
あちらこちらに作ったシンボルは勝ち取った平和の証
The symbols we built here and there are proof of the peace we won.
それすら未来でいつか私が一人にならないように
Even those were left as markers so that I won't be alone in the future,
あの旅を思い出せるように残された目印
so that I can remember that journey.
まるで御伽の話終わり迎えた証
Just like a fairy tale, proof of reaching the end.
私を変えた出会い百分の一の旅路
The encounter that changed me, a journey of one percent.
君の勇気をいつか風がさらって
Even if the wind sweeps away your courage one day,
誰の記憶から消えてしまっても
and it vanishes from everyone's memory,
私が未来に連れていくから
I will carry it with me into the future.
君の手を取ったあの日全て始まった
Everything began that day when I took your hand.
くだらなくて思わずふっと笑ってしまうような
The trivial moments that make me break into a smile,
ありふれた時間が今も眩しい
those ordinary times are still dazzling now.
知りたいんだ今更だって振り返るとそこにはいつでも
I want to know, even now, because whenever I look back,
優しく微笑みかける君がいるから
you are always there, smiling gently at me.
新たな旅の始まりは
The start of a new journey
君が守り抜いたこの地に
in this land that you protected,
芽吹いた命と
along with the life
共に
that has budded here.
そばかす
作詞：YUKI　作曲：恩田快人
Sobakasu (Freckles)
Lyrics: YUKI, Composition: Yoshihito Onda
大キライだったそばかすをちょっと
I'd touch the freckles I hated so much,
ひとなでしてタメ息をひとつ
and let out a little sigh.
ヘヴィー級の恋は見事に
That heavyweight love
角砂糖と一緒に溶けた
melted away perfectly, just like a sugar cube.
前よりももっとやせた胸にちょっと
The thorn that prickles
チクっとささるトゲが痛い
my chest, now thinner than before, hurts a bit.
星占いもあてにならないわ
I can't even rely on horoscopes anymore.
もっと遠くまで一緒にゆけたら
If only we could have gone much further together...
ねぇ
Hey,
うれしくてそれだけで
I'd be happy just with that.
想い出はいつもキレイだけど
Memories are always beautiful, but
それだけじゃおなかがすくわ
that alone isn't enough to satisfy me.
本当はせつない夜なのに
Even though it's actually a painful night,
どうしてかしら？
I wonder why?
あの人の笑顔も
I can't even remember
思い出せないの
that person's smile.
それがあたしの性格だから
Because that's just my personality.
もどかしい気持ちで
With these irritating feelings,
あやふやなままで
Remaining so vague,
それでもいい 恋をしてきた
But even so, I've been in love.
おもいきりあけた
I opened it wide,
左耳のピアスには
In the piercing on my left ear.
ねえ 笑えないエピソード
Hey, there's a story I can't laugh about.
そばかすの数を数えてみる
I try counting my freckles,
汚れたぬいぐるみ抱いてる
Holding onto a dirty stuffed animal.
胸を刺すトゲは消えないけど
The thorn pricking my heart won't go away, but...
カエルちゃんも ウサギちゃんも
Froggy and Bunny,
笑ってくれるの
Both smile for me.
想い出はいつも キレイだけど
Memories are always beautiful, but...
それだけじゃ おなかがすくの
That alone just makes me hungry.
本当は せつない夜なのに
Truth is, even on such a painful night,
どうしてかしら あの人の涙を
Why is it, I wonder? His tears...
思い出せないの
I can't remember them.
どうしてなの?
Why is it?
Shangri-La
流れに身を任せ
Leaving ourselves to the flow,
いつか大人になってゆく
We eventually become adults.
少しずつ汚れてゆく事なの?
Does that mean we slowly become tainted?
熟した果実だけ選ばれて
Only the ripe fruits are chosen,
ナイフで裂かれて 飲み込まれる前に
Before being cut by a knife and swallowed whole.
僕等目指した Shangri-La
The Shangri-La we aimed for,
欲望は抑えきれずに
Unable to suppress our desires,
空想にまみれた 自由を求め続けた
Covered in daydreams, we kept seeking freedom.
今なら言えるだろう 此処が理想郷さ
Now I can say it, this is the utopia.
さよなら 蒼き日々よ
Farewell, those youthful days.
大切な何かを 踏み台にまでしても
Even if we have to step on something precious...
一番高い林檎　掴みたかった
I wanted to grab the highest apple
失くしてから気付く　尊いモノ
Realizing its value only after losing it
幼い僕等は　的外れだらけさ
We were young and filled with irrelevance
満ち足りた日々の制圧は
The suppression of fulfilled days
情緒不安定になる
Becomes emotionally unstable
傷を負ってでも
Even with wounds
羽ばたきたいと願うよ
I wish to fly
愚かでいいのだろう
It's okay to be foolish
見渡す夢の跡
The traces of dreams as far as the eye can see
さよなら　蒼き日々よ
Goodbye, blue days
輝く空は　無邪気そう装い
The shining sky pretends to be innocent
落陽を待ち伏せしていた
Lurking in wait for the sunset
僕等は目指した Shangri-La
We aimed for Shangri-La
欲望は抑えきれずに
Unable to suppress our desires
空想にまみれた
Covered in fantasies
自由を求め続けた
Continuing to seek freedom
距離をおいてこそ
Only by keeping distance
自分の大きさを知る
Do you realize your own size
未熟な心は
An immature heart
それさえ分からないまま
Without even understanding that
今なら言えるだろう
Now I can say it
此処がそう楽園さ
This place is paradise
さよなら　蒼き日々よ
Goodbye, blue days
遥か空響いてる　祈りは奇跡に
Resonating in the distant sky, a prayer becomes a miracle
ETERNAL BLAZE
このライブも、もう折り返しに来てます！
This live is already halfway through!
みんな、まだまだ、まだまだ盛り上がっていけるよね！
Everyone, we can still, still, still get more hyped, right!
真夜中の蒼に溶けて
Melting into the midnight blue
流れてく涙の粒
Streaming drops of tears
迷いなく包み込むぬくもりに出会った
I met a warmth that envelops without hesitation
真っ白な雪のようにどこまでも素直な言葉
Words as honest as pure white snow
鉄の羽纏った僕を動かしてく
They set me in motion, clad in iron wings
傷つくたびに優しくなれる
Every time I get hurt, I can become kinder
君のその笑顔だけ守り抜きたい
I want to protect only your smile
願いはひとつ
There is only one wish
時空を越え刻まれた悲しみの記憶
Memories of sadness carved across time and space
まっすぐに受け止める君は光の女神
You, accepting everything head-on, are the goddess of light
あの日胸に灯った永遠の炎
The eternal flame lit in my heart that day
深い闇解き放って自由のトビラ開いてく
Releasing the deep darkness, opening the door to freedom
強く果てない未来へ
Toward a strong and endless future
冷たい緑の月に映し出す心の影
The shadow of the heart reflected on the cold green moon
淋しげに呟いた君の傍にいたい
I want to be by your side, as you whispered lonely
真実と向き合うこと
Facing the truth
教えてくれた勇気は
The courage you taught me
僕を駆け巡って
Rushes through me
夢に目覚めてゆく
Awakening to a dream
触れ合う気持ち
The feelings that touch
離れないように
So they won't drift apart
しっかりと抱きしめて
Hold them tight
確かな想い
A certain feeling
貫いてゆく
I will see it through
銀の海に隠した
Hidden in a silver sea
空白のページ
A blank page
君だけが知っている
Only you know
「本当」を僕に見せて
Show me the "truth"
吹き荒れる切なさに
In the raging sorrow
生まれゆく誓い
A vow is born
もう何も怖くはないよ
I'm not afraid of anything anymore
結んだ視線
Our locked eyes
そらさずに
Without looking away
大切な今 始める
I start this precious "now"
Eternal Blaze!!
自分で
By myself
君で
With you
いられる場所
A place where we can be ourselves
悪夢-まぼろし-に
To a nightmare or phantom
さらわれぬように
So we're not snatched away
消えない雨の
Of the unending rain
苦しみも
The suffering too
鍵を壊して
Break the lock
ぶつけてよ
Release it all
隣にいるから
Because I'm by your side
すべてを信じて
Believe in everything
時を越え刻まれた
Etched across time
悲しみの記憶
Memories of sadness
まっすぐに受け止める
I'll take them head-on
君は光の女神
You are the goddess of light
あの日胸に灯った
That day, lit in my chest
永遠の炎
The eternal flame
深い闇
Deep darkness
解き放って
Set it free
自由のトビラ開いてく
Opening the door to freedom
強く果てない未来へ
To a strong and endless future
そう きっとここから始まる
Yes, it surely starts from here
伝説の朝に
On that legendary morning
誓い合った言葉
The words we vowed to each other
分かち合う声に
In our shared voices
流星を照らせ
Let the shooting stars shine
革命を Let's shout
Revolution, let's shout
風の舞う光の空
In the sky of light where the wind dances
吹き抜けろ Zant
Blow through, Zant
この右手と
With this right hand
この左手
And this left hand
何を求める?
What do you seek?
魂の数理に
In the logic of the soul
焦がれた感情
Longed-for emotions
重ね合えば
If we overlap them
繋ぎ合えば
If we connect them
伝うのか
Will they reach?
運命に委ね
Entrusting to fate
流れのままに
Going with the flow
抗う情熱
Resisting passion
燃えろ熱く
Burn hotly
震わせよ
Let it tremble
響き放て
Release the echo
交差する
Crossing
プリズムのように
Like a prism
革命のデュアリズム
Revolutionary dualism
さあ始めよう
Now, let's begin
一瞬で全霊の咆哮
In an instant, a wholehearted roar
届いていますか?
Is it reaching you?
化学反応 愛のデッドヒート
Chemical reaction, dead heat of love
ついて来い 夢の果て
Follow me to the end of the dream
どんなロードだって
No matter what road it is
いつかは交わりあう
Someday they will cross
その日
On that day
君はジャッジメントする
You will make the judgment
革命を Let's shout
Revolution, let's shout
Plus minus zero
揺るがない Tuning
Unwavering tuning
罪みたいに深くした
Deepened like a sin
色褪せない Dream 神様は希望を与え
Fadeless dream, God gives hope
痛みをボカして
Blurring the pain
何を守り
What to protect
何を信じ
What to believe
生きろという
Telling us to live
未来へのドアは
The door to the future
この手の中にしかないさ
Is only in these hands
残酷を選べ
Choose cruelty
暁の君
You of the dawn
虹のかかる
Where a rainbow hangs
見たことない
A never-before-seen
絶景のプライド 教えてやる
Superb view of pride, I'll teach you
覚醒のデュアリズム
Awakening dualism
さあ飛び込もう
Now, let's dive in
百花繚乱 カオスな衝動
All kinds of flowers blooming, chaotic impulse
リベラルを散らして
Scattering the liberal
胸のフレーム 叩く鼓動
Heartbeat pounding in the chest's frame
どこまで行けるのか
How far can we go
変わらない何かで
With something unchanging
何度も口づけした
Kissed many times
そして
And then
君はまた恋に出会う
You encounter love again
Trust my heart
Just be my heart
Oh duel...
誇り高き愛の結晶
A noble crystallization of love
握り締めたら
If I hold it tight
迎えに行くから
I'll come to pick you up
切なこの一生さ
This painful life
全て見せてきた
I've shown everything
君へのラスト
The last for you
Break up
壊されていけ
Be destroyed
どこへ行けよ
Where should I go
一瞬 電光石火の咆哮 轟いて 今すぐ
In an instant, lightning-fast roar, resound right now
化学反応
Chemical reaction
愛がデストロイ
Love is destroyed
ついて来い
Follow me
夢の果て
To the end of the dream
乱乱乱舞って
Dancing wildly
いつか混じり合う日は
The day we'll eventually merge
君はジャッジメントする
You will make the judgment
革命を Let's shout!
Revolution, let's shout!
佐賀... 佐賀... 佐賀...
Saga... Saga... Saga...
佐賀事変
作詞：古屋真 作曲：原一博
Saga Incident
Lyrics: Shin Furuya Composition: Kazuhiro Hara
一雫のくちびる
A single drop of lips
塗り直した真夜中
Midnight repainted
今夜は来る来ない かわいてゆく
Whether it comes or not tonight, it's drying up
七枚花びらちぎって
Tearing off seven petals
リンドー リンドー
Gentian, gentian
信望バラバラ何それ
Broken faith, what's that?
捕らわれの時計
Captive clock
少しハッピー心中
A slightly happy double suicide
すぐに立てるわさ
I can stand up soon
笑われ自棄するなら その手で奪って
If you're laughed at and act out of desperation, take it with those hands
ホーマホーマ 愛憎ぐるぐる来なよ
Homahoma, love and hate swirling, come here
泣いて 泣いて
Cry, cry
避難し？
Seeking refuge?
アブクジャブジャブ紐切れた
Bubbles splashing, the string broke
赤い鮮血で結ばれ
Bound by red fresh blood
見せつけ遂げた罠逆らいて
Opposing the trap that was shown and accomplished
地獄だって会いに来て
Even if it's hell, come to see me
風吹かれ あられ 逃れ 絶砕
Blown by the wind, hail, escaping, absolute crushing
音符カップルの街中
In the middle of a town of musical note couples
口説き文句の飛び交い
Seductive phrases flying around
私だけわからんと すぐに来て防いで
Saying only I don't understand, come quickly and prevent it
タイノタイノ 境界はるばる乗り越え
Tainotaino, crossing boundaries from afar
舞え 舞え
Dance, dance
おこしやす
Welcome
涙ドロイド百花の無限大
Tears android, infinity of a hundred flowers
雨ニモマケズ葬られな
Be buried without losing to the rain
琴線ドプドプガラガラに開いて
Opening the heartstrings wide and rattling
甘い前に潤して
Moisten before it gets sweet
来る来ない 狂い 濁れ
Coming or not, go crazy, get muddy
ダッダッダーリナ ダッダッダラーッタッ
Da dda dda rina da dda dda ra tta
ダーリノ ダーリノ ダッダラーッタッ
Da rino da rino da dda ra tta
ダーラダッ ダッダッダラーッタッ
Da ra da dda dda dda ra tta
ダーリノ ダーリノ ダーリノ ダーラッ
Da rino da rino da rino da ra
ダラララリラッ
Da ra ra ra ri ra
止めどなき感情 吐き出したい
Unstoppable emotions, I want to let them out
Back to back to back to back...
鼓動が 何時までも 震えていたい
I want my heart to keep trembling forever
愛ゆえ狂う定めならば
If it is our fate to go mad for love
時を超えて交わる
We will meet across time
熱く焦がすほど の知れ合いたい
I want to know you so much it burns
Back to back to back to back...
赤い鮮血で 結ばれたい
I want to be bound by red blood
Bye bye bye bye bye bye...
満たさぬ棘を笑わば超えて
If they laugh at the unfulfilled thorns, overcome them
地獄立って相見えて
Meeting even in the depths of hell
重ねた運命の行方
The destination of our overlapping fates
比類なき情意で
With unparalleled affection
甘い未来など要らぬ
I don't need a sweet future
抱き合いて溺れても
Even if we drown in each other's arms
チッキラン チッキラン チッキラン チッキラン
Chikkiran chikkiran chikkiran chikkiran
高嶺ルイちゃんでした！ありがとう！
That was Takane Lui! Thank you!
かなた先輩、お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Kanata-senpai, happy birthday!
一緒に歌えて嬉しかったです。
I was so happy to sing with you.
ありがとう！またね！
Thank you! See you later!
聖少女領域 / 作詞:宝野アリカ 作曲:片倉三起也
Seishoujo Ryouiki / Lyrics: Arika Takano, Composition: Mikiya Katakura
まだ言わないで
Don't say it yet
呪文めいたその言葉
Those words like a magic spell
「愛」なんて
Something like "love"
羽のように軽い
Is as light as a feather
囁いて
Whisper to me
パパより優しい手つきで
With a touch gentler than a father's
脱がせて
Take it off
覚悟があるのならば
If you have the resolve
百万の薔薇の寝床に
In a bed of a million roses
埋もれ見る夢よりも
Rather than the dreams seen buried there
馨しく私は生きてるの
I am living more fragrantly
汚れれば
If it becomes defiled
醜いものがはびこった この世界
In this world where ugly things have run rampant
汚れずに
Without being defiled
はばたいて行けるのか
Can I keep flying?
ひとり繭の中
Alone inside a cocoon
学びつづけても
Even if I continue to learn
水晶の星空は
The crystal starry sky
遠すぎるの
Is far too distant
まだ触れないで
Don't touch me yet
その震える指先は
Those trembling fingertips
花盗みの
Are like a flower-stealer's
甘い躊躇い
Sweet hesitation
触れていい
You may touch me
この深い胸の奥まで
If you have the confidence
届く自信があるのならば
To reach the depths of my heart
白馬の王子様なんて
A prince on a white horse?
信じてるわけじゃない
It's not that I believe in such a thing
緋に染まった
Stained in scarlet
ガラスケースに飾られた
Displayed in a glass case
純潔は
My purity
滅びゆく天使たちの心臓
Is the heart of perishing angels
また明日も
Again tomorrow
目醒めるたびに
Every time I wake up
百年の刻を知る
I learn of a hundred years of time
眠れない
Unsleeping
魂の茨姫
Sleeping beauty of the soul
重すぎる冠
A crown too heavy
ひと滴の血に
In a single drop of blood
あえかな真実を
I come to know
想い知るの
The fragile truth
まだ行かないで
Don't go yet
月明かりの結界
The barrier of moonlight
過ちに気づいてしまいそう
I feel I might notice the mistake
安らかな温もりに
I want to be embraced
抱かれ壊れたい
In peaceful warmth and break
私は罪の子なのでしょうか
Am I a child of sin?
そっとこぼれてくる
I don't even know the meaning
涙の意味さえわからない
Of the tears that softly spill
呪文めいたその言葉 愛なんて
That word that sounds like a spell... "Love"...
鎖のように重い
is heavy as a chain.
甘やかして撫でるより
Rather than spoiling and petting me...
どんな覚悟もできるならば
if you can make any kind of resolve...
震える唇で蜜を摘む
With trembling lips, plucking nectar...
狩人のときめき
is the hunter's thrill.
この深い胸の奥底を
If you have the courage
射抜く勇気があるのならば
to shoot through the depths of this heart...
あなた捕まえただけじゃ
I didn't just catch you.
逃がさないようにして
I'll make sure you can't escape.
ありがとう！
Thank you!
はい！ということで
Yes! So...
百鬼先輩、AZKiちゃん、そしてラプラスが来てくれました！ありがとう！
Nakiri-senpai, AZKi-chan, and La+ came to perform! Thank you!
ということで、次の曲はオリジナル曲を歌いたいと思います！
So, for the next song, I'd like to sing an original song!
今日このライブのあとにアニメーションMVが投稿される...
After this live today, an animation MV will be posted...
おらくる！
Oracle!
みんなー！まだまだ盛り上がれますかー！？
Everyone! Can you still get hyped up!?
あともう少しでこのライブも終わってしまいます！
This live will be over in just a bit more!
最後まで全力出して盛り上がっていくぞー！
Let's get hyped up with all our strength until the end!
ヒトヒトで埋まった商店街賑わってた
The shopping district was bustling with crowds of people.
追い込んじゃったんだ
I've been backed into a corner.
チカチカって真っ赤な電灯消そうか
Shall we turn off the flickering, bright red light?
運んでいた いなくなっちゃったった
It was carrying... now they're all gone.
カンカランとカンカラ鳴った信号が鳴ってた
The signal went 'clink-clank' and rang out.
突っ立っちゃってんだ
I'm just standing there.
フラフラと真っ青なお面そやつ連れてないですか
Staggering with a bright blue mask, don't you have that guy with you?
あれあれ聞こえますか それ吐き出しちゃいますか どうぞ
Hey hey, can you hear? Shall we spit it out? Go ahead.
欠陥品と嘲笑して ろくでなしと見下して
Mocked as a defective product, looked down on as a scoundrel...
あの日けなした壊滅は自分の方でした
The one I ridiculed that day... it was actually me who was destroyed.
あらあら剥いて だんだん希望になれ
Peel it off, bit by bit, and become hope.
根本的な良い子になるまで愛してあげるね
I'll love you until you become a good child at your core.
大丈夫 強欲で満たして ぶつぶつに恋で肥やして
It's okay, fill it with greed, and fatten it up with fragmented love.
骨の髄まで ちゃんと奥まで ちゃんと愛愛愛ラブユー
To the marrow of your bones, deep inside... truly love, love, love, I love you.
足りない 足りない こっち足りない ママに甘えちゃって
Not enough, not enough, not enough over here. Being pampered by Mama.
愛しいね 可愛いね おめめに映った有象無象が全部理想
How dear, how cute. All the rabble reflected in those eyes is ideal.
君が遣わした言の葉まさに 撫で撫でしてあげるから
I'll give those words you sent a nice headpat.
こっちおいで愛お上手だね （へっほっえっほっ）
Come here, you're so good at loving. (He-ho-e-ho)
やらねばね 息が吸えたね 息が吐けたね 一人きりで今日もお過ごしてね
Gotta do it, right? You could breathe in, you could breathe out. Spending another day all alone.
意味が上手だね 口が上手だね 泣いた顔もキュンときちゃって
You're so good at meanings, so good with words. Even your crying face makes my heart flutter.
あぁ、君の存在から放たれたすべてが間違いだし正しいし有り得ないぐらいもう愛しくて愛しくて堪らないんだけど、多分１％も伝わらないからこれからも君の上から、いくらでもいくらでもいくらでも注いであげるからね、ちゅー
Ah, everything released from your existence is wrong yet right, and I love it so much I can't stand it, but since probably not even 1% gets across, from now on, I'll pour it over you from above, as much as I want, as much as I want, as much as I want, mwah.
しゃーないね しゃーないね 君のせいじゃないもんね
It's inevitable, it's inevitable. It's not your fault, is it?
しゃーないね しゃーないね ねんねしたいよね もういっちょ
It's inevitable, it's inevitable. You want to go night-night, right? One more time.
しゃーないね しゃーないね 泣いても泣いても来ないね
It's inevitable, it's inevitable. No matter how much you cry, no one comes.
しゃーないね しゃーないね 誰も返事しないもんね あー
It's inevitable, it's inevitable. No matter who you cry to, no one answers. Ah...
あらあら もうそんな傷つけたりしないで
Oh dear, don't hurt them like that anymore.
こんなバケモノだらけの世界に生んじゃってごめんね
Sorry for bringing you into this world full of monsters.
大丈夫 安全圏に行こうね 安心な世界に行こうね
It's okay, let's go to the safe zone. Let's go to a peaceful world.
居させないから ずっと今日も 一緒
I won't let you stay there, always, today too, together.
あらあら剥いて だんだん希望になれ
Peel it off, bit by bit, and become hope.
根本的な善になるまで愛してあげるね
I'll love you until you become a good person at your core.
大丈夫 強欲で満たして ぶつぶつに恋で肥やして
It's okay, fill it with greed, and fatten it up with fragmented love.
忘れちゃうから 笑っちゃうから ちゃんと愛愛愛ラブユー
Since you'll forget, since you'll laugh... truly love, love, love, I love you.
花の塔
作詞・作曲 さユり
Hana no Tou (Tower of Flowers)
Lyrics and Composition: Sayuri
君が持ってきた漫画
The manga you brought with you
くれた知らない名前の花
And the flowers with names I didn't know you gave me
今日はまだ来ないかな?
I wonder if they'll come today?
初めての感情 知ってしまった
I've learned a feeling for the first time
窓に飾った絵画をなぞって
Tracing the painting by the window
1人で宇宙を旅して
Traveling through space alone
それだけで
That should have
いいはずだったのに
been enough, but...
君の手を握ってしまったら
Once I've taken your hand
孤独を知らないこの街には
In this city that doesn't know loneliness
もう二度と帰ってくることはできないのでしょう
I probably won't be able to return ever again
君が手を差し伸べた
You reached out your hand
光で影が生まれる
Shadows are born from light
歌って聴かせて
Sing to me
この話の続き
the continuation of this story
連れていって
Take me
みたことない
to a star
星まで
I've never seen before
誰の手も声も届かない
Where no one's hand or voice can reach
高く聳え立った塔の上へ
Atop the tower that stands tall
飛ばす風船葛
Flying balloon vines
僕は君に笑ってほしいんだ
I want you to smile
満たされない穴は
The hole that can't be filled
惰性な会話や澄ましたポーズで
With idle conversation or a composed pose
これまでは埋めてきたけれど
I've filled it until now, but...
退屈な日々を
Kicking away
蹴散らして
the boring days
君と二人で
Together with you
この街中を
through this city
泳げたら
How wonderful
それはどれだけ
it would be
素敵なことでしょう
if we could swim through it
出したことないほど大きな
Louder than I've ever produced
声でやっと君に伝わる
My voice finally reaches you
歪なぐらいがきっとちょうどいいわ
A little distorted is probably just right
世界の端と
Connecting
端を結んで
the ends of the world
窓に飾った絵画をなぞって
Tracing the painting by the window
1人で宇宙を旅して
Traveling through space alone
それだけでもう不自由ないけど
I'm already satisfied with just that, but...
僕は選んでみたいの
I want to choose
沸き上がる心 謎だらけの空を
the surging heart and the mysterious sky
安全なループを今
The safe loop, now
書き換えて！
rewrite it!
君の手を握ってしまったら
Once I've taken your hand
孤独を知らない
In this city that doesn't know
この街には
loneliness
もう二度と
I probably won't
帰ってくることはできない
be able to return ever again
のでしょう
will I?
いくらでも迷いながら
While getting lost as much as we like
光も影も
Both the light
見に行こう
and the shadows, let's go see them
歌って聴かせて
Sing to me
この話の続き
the continuation of this story
連れていって
Take me
みたことない
to a star
星まで
I've never seen before
世界の端と
Connecting
端を結んで
the ends of the world
ラスト1曲、この5人で歌わせていただきました！
For the last song, the five of us performed it for you!
ありがとうございましたー！
Thank you very much!
（歌唱）
(Singing)
うおー！
Woo-hoo!
いえーい！ バイバイ！
Yay! Bye-bye!
バイバイ！
Bye-bye!
ありがとうー！
Thank you!
皆さん、天音かなた誕生日記念ライブ、
Everyone, how was Amane Kanata's
いかがでしたでしょうか？ 楽しんでいただけたでしょうか？
birthday celebration live? Did you enjoy it?
こちら、誕生日記念2024グッズも、もちろん出ますとも！
Of course, the Birthday Celebration 2024 goods
are coming out as well!
こちらが誕生日記念のフルセットでございます。グッズフルセット。
This is the birthday celebration full set.
The goods full set.
今後ね、今後じゃねーや、この後ね、あのね、
Later on—not later, right after this—
全部細かく紹介したいと思いますが...
I want to introduce everything in detail, but...
まず言いたいのは、数量限定バージョンがございます！
First, I want to say that there is
a limited quantity version!
直筆サインが入ったもの、えー、そして、
One with a handwritten signature, and...
箔押し複製サインのメッセージ入りポストカードが入ったものと...
one with a foil-stamped replica signature
and message postcard...
2種類ございます。よろしくお願いします。
There are two types available.
Please check them out.
はい。えー、そして、まずグッズです。アクリルパネル。
Yes. Next, the goods. This acrylic panel...
こちらキラキラホログラム仕様ということで、キラキラ光りますので、
features a sparkling hologram design,
so it sparkles.
よろしくお願いします。光るっていうのは、こう、なんか、角度変えたら光る、だけ、光る感じ。
Please check it out. By "sparkling", I mean it
shines when you change the angle.
あ！ はい！ ランダムステッカーやん。
Oh! Yes! Random stickers.
こちら全4種類からランダムに1枚封入される...
One of four types is included at random...
ランダムステッカーでございます。スマホの裏とかにね、ぜひ貼ってください。よろしくお願いいたしまーす。
These are random stickers. Please put them
on the back of your smartphone. Thank you very much.
あ！ こちら、かなたそさんぬい、かなたそちゃんぬいぐるみでございます。
Oh! This is the Kanata-so plushie,
the Kanata-so-chan plushie.
これね、マジで超可愛いから、あの、ぜひね、色んなところにお出かけ一緒に連れてってあげてください。
This is seriously super cute, so please take
it with you when you go out.
そして、そして、むにむに待ちうぱおキーホルダー。
And, and, the Squishy Waiting Upao Keychain.
うぱおがこれね、完全にむにむにを待っております。
Upao is completely waiting to be squished.
本当、むにむにしてるんです。ぜひこのキーホルダーもね、あの、なんか、付けてくださいな。
It's really squishy. Please attach this
keychain to something.
はい。こちらがね、全てのフルセットになっております。
Yes. This is the complete full set.
あの、個々でも単品でも買えますので、よろしくお願いいたしますね。
You can also buy individual items,
so please check them out.
はい。頑張ってサインも書かせていただきます！
Yes. I'll do my best to sign them all!
そしてこの後は、アニメーションMV、『オラクル』が投稿されます。よろしくお願いいたします！
And after this, the animated MV 'Oracle'
will be posted. Please check it out!
いや、あの、こちらね、オリジナル曲でございます。じんさんに作詞作曲していただきました。
Well, this is an original song. Jin-san wrote
the lyrics and composed it.
人、人、人で埋まった
Filled with people, people, people
このアニメーション、ちょっと考察するところがたくさんあります。おもしろいアニメーションMVになっております。
There are many things to analyze in this animation.
It's an interesting animated MV.
シャッター街　終わってた
Shuttered street, it was over
不安、不安、不安ばっか
Anxiety, anxiety, nothing but anxiety
まき直し込んじゃったんだ？
Did you get caught up in it?
アンチだって
Even the antis
赤な電灯
Red streetlights
景色変えた　能力
The ability that changed the scenery
そしておしゃれなので、ぜひぜひチェックしてくださいね。よろしくお願いいたします！
And it's very stylish, so please check it out.
Thank you!
いなくなっちゃったんだ
They've gone away
それでは皆さん、この後も盛りだくさん。グッズは22時から販売だよ！
Well then, everyone, there's a lot more to come.
Goods go on sale at 22:00!
よろしくね！ 概要欄からも飛べるから！
See ya! You can access them
from the description box!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!